Guide to the Paul A. Samuelson papers, 1933-2010 and undated RL.10082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Speeches and Interviews Series, 1980-2009, 8 boxes
  - Speeches and interviews, 1993
    - 170. "Four Cheers for Lester Thurow," in honor of Thurow's department as Dean of the Sloan School, MIT, 28 May 1993 (Box 123)
    - 171. "Realities for a Fine June Day," HBS Class Reunion of 1948, Harvard Business School, Cambridge, Mass., 5 June 1993 (Box 123)
    - 172. "Optimal Federal Reserve Policy for 1993-94," Testimony Before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs, Washington, DC, 1 July 1993 (Box 123)
    - 173. Skipped (Box 123)
    - 174. "Economic Roadblocks on the Road Joining America and Japan," NYU Lecture, 23 September 1993 (Box 123)
    - 175. "The Second Clinton Year," Boston Economics Club, Boston, Mass., 29 September 1993 (Box 123)
    - 176. "Introduction to Black-Scholes Anniversary Picnic," MIT, 8 October 1993 (Box 123)
    - 177. "A Distant Danger. Will President Clinton Turn Protectionist?" NYU Lecture, 18 October 1993 (Box 123)
    - 178. "Global Marketing," Sloan Senior Executives Forum, 22 October 1993 (Box 123)
    - 179. "The Past and Future of International Trade Theory," keynote speech at Conference on New Directions in Trade Theory, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 29-30 October 1993 (Publication No. 1741) (Box 123)
    - 180. Statement on NAFTA at The White House, Washington, DC, 2 November 1993 (Box 123)
    - 181. "NAFTA, Autos and the General Welfare," NYU Lecture, 5 November 1993 (Box 123)
    - 182. "Reflections on Investing for Foundations and Colleges," U.S. Trust/Rutgers University Endowment and Foundations Seminar, New York, 17 November 1993 (Box 123)
    - 183. "The U.S. and Global Economy," SPURS Program, MIT, 1 December 1993 (Box 123)
    - 184. "U.S. and Japan: International Competitiveness," NYU Lecture, 8 December (Box 123)
  - Speeches and interviews, 1994
    - 185. "Me and Kennedy," The Examiner Club, Boston, Mass., 3 January 1994 (Includes audio cassette) (Box 123)
    - 186. "Japan-U.S. Financial Developments After the Kosokawa-Clinton Debacle," NYU Lecture, 15 February 1994 (Box 123)
    - 187. "Economic Science Grapples with Current Problems," Undergraduate Economic Association, MIT, 17 March 1994 (Box 123)
    - 188. No copy (Box 123)
    - 189. "Budget Constraints That Are Not Soft," NYU Technical Symposium luncheon speech, 24 March 1994 (Published) (Box 123)
    - 190. "Strange Time: U.S. Leads the World Pack," MIT Senior Executives, Endicott House, Dedham, Mass., 28 March 1994 (Box 123)
    - 191. "Global Financial Problems and Prospects," NYU Panel, 11 April 1994 (Box 123)
    - 191a. "Shaping a Future Order for Japanese Foreign Investment," 14 April 1994 (Box 123)
    - 192. "International Investing," NYU Lecture, 20 April 1994 (Box 123)
    - 193. "Interview (in Italian) in La Repubblica, 3 March 1994 (Box 123)
    - 194. "Strong American Recovery and the Weak Global Picture," Sloan Fellows, MIT, 26 April 1994 (Box 123)
    - 195. Remarks by Paul A. Samuelson to Italian Bankers Visiting Boston-MIT, 9 May 1994 (Box 123)
    - 196. Interview (in Italian) for Il Secolo XIX, April 1994 (Box 123)
    - 197. "Macroeconomics Progresses But Still Falls Short," Boston Association of Business Economists, Boston, Mass., 12 May 1994 (Box 123)
    - 198. "World at the Turn of the Century," WEL Conference, Milano, Italy, 23 May 1994 (Box 123)
    - 199. "Fuzzy Facts About the Mayer Lypski Clan," Family Reunion, Chicago, Ill., 16 July 1994 (Box 123)
    - 200. Robert Merton's Fiftieth Birthday Party, Boston Harbor Hotel, 30 July 1994 (Box 123)
    - 201. Panel for Newcomers to MIT, MIT, 31 August 1994 (Box 123)
    - 202. Interview (in Italian) in La Repubblica, 18 August 1994 (Box 123)
    - 203. "Japan-U.S. Relations in Clinton's Second Year," NYU Lecture, 21 September 1994 (Box 123)
    - 204. Panel Discussion on Business History and Economics, Harvard Business School, 26 September 1994 (Box 123)
    - 205. "The U.S. Economy in the Clinton Era," MIT Senior Executives, Endicott House, Dedham, Mass., 3 October 1994 (Box 123)
    - 206. "A Bouquet of Fallacies and Facts in the Science Fiction and Science of Investing," Cambridge Center for Behavioral Sciences, Cambridge, Mass., 5 October 1994 (Box 123)
    - 207. Interview (in Chinese) in Economic Highlights, 30 June 1994 (Box 123)
    - 208. Interview (in Italian) in L'Indice, July 1994 (Box 123)
    - 209. No copy (Box 123)
    - 210. "Trade and Competitiveness Now That Japan Comes of Age," NYU Lecture, 24 October 1994 (Box 123)
    - 211. Toast to Journal of Portfolio Management at Twenty," Comments at celebration, New York, 3 November 1994 (Box 123)
    - 212. "Japan-U.S. Current Financial Trends," NYU Lecture, 2 November 1994 (Box 123)
    - 213. "Henk Houthakker," Toast at his retirement dinner, Harvard Faculty Club, Cambridge, Mass., 2 December 1994 (Box 123)
    - 214. "What Fiscal Coordination Ought to Mean," NYU Lecture, 5 December 1994 (Box 123)
  - Speeches and interviews, 1995
    - 215. "The Economics of Disasters: Japan After the Kobe Earthquake," NYU Lecture, 6 February 1995 (Box 123)
    - 216. "New Directions in Japanese Financial Structures, NYU Lecture, 21 March 1995 (Box 123)
    - 217. No copy (Box 123)
    - 218. "At Eighty," For Family Party, 17 April 1995 (Box 123)
    - 219. Untitled, NYU Panel on Competition and Cooperation in Information Technology: The Japanese Experience, 18 April 1995 (Box 123)
    - 220. "The 60-Year Sure Thing and Other Doubtful Theories," Boston Globe, by David Warsh, 23 April 1995 (Box 123)
    - 221. "At Eighty: MIT and I," MIT 80th Birthday Party, Boston Harbor Hotel, 30 April 1995 (Box 123)
    - 222. "Crisis for the Welfare State," Harvard Law School, 3 May 1995 (Box 123)
    - 223. "Requiem for Robert Solow on Retirement," American Academy of Atts & Sciences, Cambridge, Mass., 6 May 1995 (Box 123)
    - 224. "Grappling with Rational Case for Long-Horizon Risky-Equities Tolerance, University of Rome, Rome, Italy, 5 April 1995 (Box 123)
    - 225. "The Economic Road Ahead," Finnish Executives Seminar, Boston, 5 June 1995 (Box 123)
    - 226. "The Economic World that the Sloan School Faces in its Second Half Century," Sloan School Alumni, MIT, 17 June 1995 (Box 123)
    - 227. Interview for Mainichi Shimbun (Japanese "Economist") June/July, 1995 (Box 123)
    - 228. Paul A. Samuelson mentioned/interviewed for "How Safe Are Stocks?" Institutional Investor, March 1995, p. 133 (Box 123)
    - 228a. "Crisis for Welfare State," Harvard Law School, 3 May 1995 (Box 123)
    - 229. Interview for Korean TV, 28 August 1995 (Includes VHS tape) (Box 123)
    - 230. "The Next Fifty Years of Japan-U.S. Economic Relations," NYU Lecture, 26 September 1995 (Box 123)
    - 231. "Deja Vu: Being 80 All Over Again," Birthday Party, NYU, 26 September 1995 (Box 123)
    - 232. "Tribute to Herbert Scarf," Yale University, 30 September 1995 (Box 123)
    - 233. "An Overview of Japan-U.S. Trade Relations," NYU Panel on Japanese Investment, Past and Present, 9 October 1995 (Box 123)
    - 234. "A Distant Danger: Will President Clinton Turn Protectionist?" NYU Panel on Trade Relations Between Japan and the U.S.: An Overview, 18 October 1995 (Box 123)
    - 235. "The Fulfilled Life," Honorary Society inductees, Concord-Carlisle High School, Concord, Mass., 6 November 1995 (Box 123)
    - 236. "Leontief at Ninety," NYU Birthday Celebration, New York, 27 November 1995 (Box 123)
    - 237. "Introducing the Debaters Who Argue About Whether Risk Averages Down in the Long Run," Financial Engineers Dinner, Cambridge, Mass., 30 November 1995 (Box 123)
    - 238. "Japan-U.S. Macroeconomics Coordination," NYU Panel on Fiscal & Monetary Coordination: Japan-U.S. Dimensions, 5 December 1995 (Box 123)
    - 239. Interview (in Japanese) in Nihon Keizai Shimbun, 21 November 1995 (Box 123)
  - Speeches and interviews, 1996
    - 240. "What Has the Economy Taught Us About Macroeconomics?" IAP Lecture, MIT, 10 January 1996 (Box 123)
    - 241. "New Directions in Industrial Competition," NYU Lecture, 21 February 1996 (Box 123)
    - 242. Interview (in Italian), Carriere della Sera, 2 Januaty 1996 (Box 123)
    - 243. "Japan's Role in Peace and Prosperity, And Ours," NYU Lecture, 5 March 1996 (Box 123)
    - 244. "Theories of the Feasible FIRST Best," NYU Technical Symposium, 29 March 1996 (Published) (Box 123)
    - 245a. "Wrong and Right Reasons for Long-Horizon Investors to be More Equity Tolerant," Mathematical Finance Day, Boston University, 31 March 1996 (Box 123)
    - 245b. "In on the Creation: The Theory of Finance Gets Born," luncheon speech read by Robert C. Merton, Mathematical Finance Day, Boston University, 31 March 1996 (Box 123)
    - 246. "Japanese Multinationals in the Global Economy," NYU Lecture, 2 April 1996 (Box 123)
    - 247. "Legacy of the New Deal," St. Botolph Club, Boston, 10 April 1996 (Box 123)
    - 248. "Shaping Economic Science to Cope with End-of-Century Reality," Undergraduate Economic Association, MIT, 17 April 1996 (Box 123)
    - 249. "Grande Come Adam Smith," interview (in Italian), Il Mondo, 27 April 1996 (Box 123)
    - 250. "American and European Economic Divergences at Century's End," Lecture at IDEI, Toulouse, France, 9 May 1996 (Includes VHS tape) (Box 123)
    - 251. "Bob Bishop at Eight," MIT Faculty Club, 2 June 1996 (Box 123)
    - 252. U.S. Treasury Talk, Washington, DC, 26 July 1996 (Box 123)
    - 253. "Dole Tax Cut," WBUR Radio, The Connection, 5 August 1996 (Includes audio cassette tape) (Box 123)
    - 254. "Changing World Order and Japan-U.S. Relations," NYU Lecture, 18 September 1996 (Box 123)
    - 255. Written answers to five questions for Academic Advisory Panel Meeting, Federal Reserve Bank of Boston, 17 September 1996 (Box 123)
    - 256. "MIT Preens Itself," MIT Department of Economics dinner honoring Paul A. Samuelson for receiving the National Medal of Science, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Cambridge, Mass., 21 September 1996 (Box 123)
    - 257. Remarks for WJON/ABC News Radio on Dole-Kemp Tax Plan (with Merton Miller), Palm Beach, Florida, 25 September 1996 (Box 123)
    - 258. "Monetary and Fiscal Stabilization for Japan and the United States," NYU Lecture, 7 October 1996 (Box 123)
    - 259. "The 1996 Elections and What They Betoken for the Japan-U.S. Dialogue," NYU Lecture, 22 October 1996 (Box 123)
    - 260. "Central Banking and Financial Markets," NYU Panel, 18 November 1996 (Box 123)
    - 261. Interview (in Japanese), Yamiuri, November, 1996 (Box 123)
    - 262. Award Acceptance Speech, Japan Chamber of Commerce and Industry of New York, New York, 21 November 1996 (Box 123)
    - 263. Questions and answers for Academic Advisory Panel meeting, Federal Reserve Bank of Boston, 12 December 1996 (Box 123)
    - 264. Toast and Introductory Remarks for TIAA-CREF Paul A. Samuelson Prize, AEA Meetings, New Orleans, 4-5 January 1997 (Box 123)
    - 265. Interview (in Italian), Carriere della Sera, 30 December 1996 (Box 123)
  - Speeches and interviews, 1997
    - 266. "Information Technology in the Global Future," NYU Lecture, 20 February 1997 (Box 123)
    - 267. "A Better Break for Small and Large Investors," NYU Lecture, 4 March 1997 (Box 123)
    - 268. "The Coming Erosion of Advanced Nations' Well-Being From World Trade," NYU Technical Symposium, 27-28 March 1997 (Box 123)
    - 269. "Business Negotiations Across Cultures," NYU Lecture, 15 April 1997 (Box 123)
    - 270. "Why Economies Grow and Why They Decay," for video teleconference for Economic Congress in Buenos Aires, Argentina, 23 April 1997 (Box 123)
    - 271. "Fifty Years On: the Marshall Plan," St. Botolph Club, Boston, Mass., 14 May 1997 (Box 124)
    - 272. "Interview (in Italian) in Milano Finanza, 31 May 1997 (Box 124)
    - 273, "Belmont Hill Tennis Club," Harvard Faculty Club, Cambridge, Mass., 30 July 1997 (Box 124)
    - 274. Interview (in Japanese) in Nikkei Business, July, 1997 (Box 124)
    - 275. "Stocks are Better Than CDs and Bonds," interview in Bovespa (magazine of the Sao Paolo Stock Exchange), Year IV, No, 44, pg. 4-11, May 1997 (Box 124)
    - 276. Interview (telephone) for Reuters Wire Service, 9 September 1997 (Box 124)
    - 277. "In on the Creation," dinner speech, International Association of Financial Engineers, Boston, Mass., 22 September 1997 (Box 124)
    - 278. "Wherein Do the European and American Models Differ?" Lecture at Banca d'Italia, Rome, 3 October 1997 (Box 124)
    - 279. "Informal Thoughts about Macroeconomics," Roundtable at Banca d'Italia, Rome, 3 October 1997 (Box 124)
    - 280. Interview for World Radio (BBC/NPR), regarding the Merton-Scholes Nobel Prize, 14 October 1997 (Includes audio cassette) (Box 124)
    - 281. "Reminiscences of Archie Cox during the 1960 Presidential Campaign," JFK Library, Boston, Mass., 22 October, 1997 (Box 124)
    - 282. "Tribute to Robert Mundell," read in Washington, DC, 23 October 1997 (Box 124)
    - 282a. Interview (in German) in Wirtschafls Woche, regarding Merton-Scholes and the 1997 Nobel Prize, October 1997 (Box 124)
    - 283. CNBC interview regarding the Merton-Scholes Nobel Prize in Economics, 14 October 1997 (Includes VHS tape) (Box 124)
    - 284. "For Eric Roll at Ninety," speech read by someone else in London on the occasion of a birthday party for Lord Roll, 3 December 1997 (Box 124)
    - 285. Notes for interview with Nihon Keizai Shimbun Japanese television, December 1997 (Box 124)
    - 286. Printed interview of "Armchair Millionaire," for web site of iVillage (Lewis Schiff), December 1997 (Box 124)
  - Speeches and interviews, 1998
    - 287. "Another Year, Another Jump Ahead for the Art of Finance," and "From TIAA-CREF and Back to It," TIAA-CREF Paul A. Samuelson Award, AEA, Chicago, 4 January 1998 (Box 124)
    - 288. "Samuelson's Economics at Fifty," McGraw-Hill celebration at AEA, Chicago, 4 January 1998 (Publication No. 1959) (Box 124)
    - 289. Interview (in Italian) in La Stampa, pg. 6, 10 January 1998 (Box 124)
    - 290. Interview (in Japanese) for Nihon Keizai Shimbun Japanese Public Television, broadcast 4 January 1998 (Box 124)
    - 291. "Recent Trends in International Banking," NYU Lecture, 24 February 1998 (Box 124)
    - 292. "Harold Freeman (1909-1997)," Memorial Service Tribute, MIT, 10 March 1998 (Includes audio cassette tape) (Box 124)
    - 293. Skipped (Box 124)
    - 294. "'Tis Folly to be Wise," interview, Dow Jones Asset Management, pg. 20-28, March/April l998 (Box 124)
    - 295. No copy (Box 124)
    - 296. "The Central Role of Telecommunications," NYU Lecture, 15 April 1998 (Box 124)
    - 297. "As Bandwagon Rolls On, There's Need to Take Heed," interview, The Boston Globe, pg. C1 and C13, 15 April 1998 (Box 124)
    - 298. Interview (in Japanese) in Yomiuri Shimbun, 15 April 1998 (Box 124)
    - 299. Interview (in Italian) in La Stampa, by telephone, 1 May 1998 (Box 124)
    - 300. Remarks at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Honorary Degree, Troy, New York, 15 May 1998 (Box 124)
    - 301. "Mathematics is a Skeleton Key in Science, Economics and Business," mathematics graduating class, Belmont Hill School, Belmont, Mass. (re Couper Samuelson), 28 May 1998 (Box 124)
    - 302. "Pitfalls in a Honeymoon Era," Institutional Investor Institute Conference luncheon speech, Boston, Mass., 12 June 1998 (Box 124)
    - 303. "When Giants Walked the Field of Finance," Memorial Symposium on Investment Perspectives for Fischer Black, New York, 23 June 1998 (Box 124)
    - 304. "Summing Up on Business Cycles," Federal Reserve Bank of Boston conference, Chatham, Mass., 24 June 1998 (Box 124)
    - 305. "Calibrating Riskiness in Terms of Certainty-Equivalents: An Alternative to the Tyranny of Mean-Variance Analysis," Chinese Finance Association keynote, MIT Faculty Club, Cambridge, Mass., 15 August 1998 (Box 124)
    - 306. "Understanding Present, Recent and Future Financial Turmoils," NYU Lecture, 1 October 1998 (Box 124)
    - 307. "Samuel Hollander, Our Master and Co-Worker," for tribute conference to Hollander, dinner speech, University of Toronto, 27-28 September 1998 (Box 124)
    - 308. "The U.S. and World Present, and Likely Future," Commercial Bank of New York, New York, 20 October 1998 (Box 124)
    - 309. "Two Gods That Failed," Heilbroner Conference, New School for Social Research, New York, 12 November 1998 (Publication No. 1957) (Box 124)
    - 310. "The Future of Industrial Structure in Japan and the U.S.," NYU Lecture, 12 November 1998 (Box 124)
    - 311. "Faculty Tribute to MIT Treasurer Glenn Strehle," MIT, 3 December 1998 (Box 124)
    - 312. Interview for Nihon Keizai Shimbun TV Broadcasting Corporation, 28 October 1998 (Includes VHS tape) (Box 124)
    - 313. "Econ 101: Is This the Best Way to Teach Economics?" interview in Federal Reserve Magazine, Minneapolis, December 1998 (Box 124)
    - 314. Interview (in Japanese) for Nihon Keizai Shimbun television documentary (Includes VHS tape) (Box 124)
  - Speeches and interviews, 1999
    - 315. "Trabalho Duro," interview (in Portugese), Exame (Brazil) by Nely Caixeta, Vol. 681, No.3, year 32, pgs. 38-42, 10 February 1999 (Box 124)
    - 316. "Is the Global Crisis Over?" Harvard and MIT Clubs of Palm Beach, Florida, 25 February 1999 (Box 124)
    - 317. "What in the World Happening to Economics?" Fortune, pgs. 91-102, 15 March 1999 (Box 124)
    - 318. "Lessons to be Learned from the Asian Financial Crisis," NYU Technical Symposium, 26 March 1999 (Box 124)
    - 319. Skipped. (Box 124)
    - 320. "Cleaning Banks' Augean Stables," NYU Lecture, 15 April 1999 (Box 124)
    - 321. "Legendary Economist," interview (in Turkish), Capital (Istanbul), pg. 68-70, May 1999 (Box 124)
    - 322. "Three Ethical Tales for Jessica," Jessica Samuelson's Bat Mitzvah, 12 June 1999 (Box 124)
    - 323. "Walter Salant," Memorial Service, Brookings Institution, Washington, DC, 21 June 1999 (Box 124)
    - 324. Statement for McGraw-Hill promotion of Chinese translation of Economics, August 1999 (Includes VHS tape) (Box 124)
    - 325. "The Narrowing of the World Market," NYU Lecture, 4 October 1999 (Publication No. 1981) (Box 124)
    - 326. Remarks, Monetary Stability and Economic Growth Conference in Honor of Randall Hinshaw, San Miguel de Allende, Mexico, videoconference, 2 October 1999 (Box 124)
    - 327. "Honoring Founding Fathers of Modern Finance Economics," Financial Management Association, Orlando, Florida, 7 October 1999 (Box 124)
    - 328. "The 'Micro Efficient' Random Walk White Noise Market," Freshman Seminar on Mutual Funds, Indexing, etc. (Poterba's class), MIT, 19 October 1999 (Box 124)
    - 329. "Economics and the Kennedy Presidency," dinner speech, The Brookings Institution, Washington, DC, 12 November 1999 (Box 124)
    - 330. "Japan's Future Financial Structure," NYU Lecture, 16 November 1999 (Publication No. 1993) (Box 124)
    - 331. Interview (in Italian) in Corriere del Ticino, Ticino, Switzerland (Lugano), 10 November 1999 (Box 124)
    - 332. "Accepting the Gold Medal from the National Institute of Social Sciences, The Metropolitan Club, New York, 1 December 1999 (Box 124)
    - 333. "What New Economics Is Needed for the New Century?" Distinguished Lecture, Fordham University, New York, 8 December 1999 (Box 124)
    - 334. Interview for BBC television, Horizon: The Midas Formula, Spring/Summer 1999 (Includes VHS tape) (Box 124)
    - 335. Interview (in Japanese) for Nihan Keizai Shimbun, 14 December 1999 (Box 125)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2000
    - 336. Remarks at TIAA-CREF Paul A. Samuelson Award, ABA, Boston, Mass., 8 January 2000 (Box 125)
    - 337. "Thanks for the J.R. Commons Award," AEA, Boston, Mass., 9 January 2000 (Box 125)
    - 338. "What May Be Ahead for the U.S. and World Economy," MIT-Wellesley Club of Southwest Florida, Sarasota Country Club, Florida, 21 January 2000 (Box 125)
    - 339. Interview (in Finnish) in Kauppalehtl, No. 21, pg. 40-43, 16 December 1999 (Box 125)
    - 340. "The Gurus, Five Eminent Economists Gaze Into the Future," invited thoughts on finance in the next 10 years, CFO Magazine, January 2000 (Box 125)
    - 341. "By Way of Warm-Up," Dean's Roundtable Dinner, University of Southern Florida/New College, Sarasota, Florida, 6 March 2000 (Box 125)
    - 342. "Some Game Theory Anecdotes," NYU Technical Symposium, 31 March 2000 (Box 125)
    - 343. "Speculations about Japan and U.S. Relations in the Coming Decade," NYU Lecture, 12 April 2000 (Publication No. 2007) (Box 125)
    - 344. Interview (in Italian) in Il Messaggero, 6 April 2000 (Box 125)
    - 345. "Some New Economics for a New Century," Brookhaven, Lexington, Mass., 17 May 2000 (Box 125)
    - 346. "Some New Economics for a New Century," Lifetime Learning, Newton, Mass., 30 May 2000 (Box 125)
    - 347. Interview (in Italian) in La Repubblica, 23 May 2000 (Box 125)
    - 348. "Modern Finance Theory Within One Lifetime," World Congress of the Bachelier Finance Society, Paris, France, 28 June 2000 (Publication No. 2090) (Box 125)
    - 349. Interview (in Japanese) in The Sankei Shimbun, 18 August 2000 (Box 125)
    - 350. "Personal Homage to Ryuzo Sato," on the occasion of a dinner at a symposium to honor his 70th birthday, Lenox, Mass., 9 September 2000 (Box 125)
    - 351. "Economic and Cultural Aspects of Tomorrow's Multinational Films," NYU Lecture, 14 September 2000 (Publication No. 2025) (Box 125)
    - 352. "Major Economic Problems in the Upcoming Decade," MIT Nobel Series (with Solow and Modigliani), 18 September 2000 (Box 125)
    - 353. Interview/article in Portuguese, Gazeta Mercantil, 23-24 September 2000 (Box 125)
    - 354. "Should We Pay Off the Debt? Exchange," with R.M. Solow, New York Review of Books, 2 November 2000 (Box 125)
    - 355. "Future Asian Stock Market Trends," NYU Lecture, 17 October 2000 (Box 125)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2001
    - 356. Remarks to be read at TIAA-CREF Paul A. Samuelson Award, AEA, New Orleans, 5 January 2001 (Box 125)
    - 357. Interview (in Flemish) in Trends magazine (Belgium), with Bob Solow, 11 January 2001 (Box 125)
    - 358. "The New Economic Ball Game," Harvard Club of Sarasota, Florida, 9 March 2001 (Box 125)
    - 359. Interview (in Korean) in Chosun Ilbo, March 2001 (Box 125)
    - 360. "Innovational Progress Sans Thrift," NYU Technical Symposium, 30 March 2001 (Publication No. 2121) (Box 125)
    - 361. Interview (in Italian) in Carriere della Sera, 23 March 2001 (Box 125)
    - 362. Interview (in Italian) in Carriere della Sera, 2 January 2001 (Box 125)
    - 363. "California Power Deregulation: Comedy or Tragedy?" NYU Lecture, 11 April 2001 (Box 125)
    - 364. Interview (in Italian) in Carriere della Sera, 20 April 2001 (Box 125)
    - 365. "The New Economic Ball Game," Undergraduate Economics Association, MIT, 9 May 2001 (Box 125)
    - 366. Interview (in Italian) in La Stampa, 4 or 5 May 2001 (Box 125)
    - 367. Comments, Academic Advisory Panel, Federal Reserve Bank of Boston, Boston, 9 May 2001 (Box 125)
    - 368. "The New Ball Game in Economics," Rotarians of Medford and Winchester, Medford, Mass., 17 May 2001 (Box 125)
    - 369. "Progress and Pitfalls in the State of Modern Finance Theory," Renaissance Technologies, East Setauket, New York, 24 May 2001 (Box 125)
    - 369a. "Is There Life After Nobel Coronation?" Contribution to Nobel e-Museum, Stockholm, Sweden, August 2001 (Box 125)
    - 370. "Innovation Technology and U.S.-Japan Recovery," NYU Lecture, 3 October 2001 (Box 125)
    - 371. "Edmund Phelps, Insider-Economists' Insider," keynote speech, Phelps Fest, Columbia University, 5 October 2001 (Publication No. 2139) (Box 125)
    - 372. Interview for Panorama Magazine (Italy), 23 September 2001 (Box 125)